Guide to the Robert Byron Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence, 1900-1991; Series I; 6.46; (16 boxes)
  - General Correspondence
    - Olivier, Edith, 1932-1933, undated (Box 12, Folder 257)
    - Ovey, Edmund, Sir, 1931-1933, undated (Box 12, Folder 258)
    - Outram, T.C., 1938-1939, undated (Box 12, Folder 259)
    - Oxford University Press, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 260)
    - "P" General, 1928-1939, undated (Box 12, Folder 261-262)
    - Pallis, Andrea, 1931-1938, undated (Box 12, Folder 263)
    - Parsons, Bridget, 1940, undated (Box 12, Folder 264)
    - Parsons, Desmond, undated (Box 12, Folder 265-266)
      Includes Byron's draft of obituary for Desmond Parsons
    - Patmore, Derek, 1932 (Box 12, Folder 267)
    - Peter Davies Limited, 1933, undated (Box 12, Folder 268)
    - Peters, A.D., 1931-1948 (Box 12, Folder 269-270)
    - Phillips, Bertram, 1939 (Box 12, Folder 271)
    - Picture Post, 1940 (Box 12, Folder 272)
    - Plimpton, K.A., 1941, undated (Box 12, Folder 273)
    - Pope, Arthur Upham, 1933-1938, undated (Box 12, Folder 274-276)
    - Pope-Hennessey, Una, 1938-1940, undated (Box 13, Folder 277)
    - Powell, Anthony, 1928 (Box 13, Folder 278)
    - Plunket, Richard and Elizabeth, Greene, 1925 (Box 13, Folder 278a)
    - Qadir, Abdul, 1934 (Box 13, Folder 279)
    - "R" General, 1930-1945, undated (Box 13, Folder 280-281)
    - Reitlinger, Gerald, undated (Box 13, Folder 282)
    - Rice, David Talbot, 1935, undated (Box 13, Folder 283)
    - Richardson, A.E. (Albert Edward), Sir, 1940-1941 (Box 13, Folder 284)
    - Richardson, E.F., 1938-1940, undated (Box 13, Folder 285)
    - Rosse, Michael Parsons, 6th Earl of, 1937-1940, undated (Box 13, Folder 286-287)
      Includes photograph of Desmond Parsons, Robert Byron, and Michael Parsons
    - Royal Central Asian Society, 1933-1938, undated (Box 13, Folder 288)
    - Royal Institute of British Architects, 1939 (Box 13, Folder 289)
    - Royal Institute of International Affairs, 1934-1942 (Box 13, Folder 290)
    - "S" General, 1924-1941, undated (Box 13, Folder 291-293)
    - Sackville-West, Edward, Hon., undated (Box 13, Folder 294)
    - Scarlett, Peter, 1934-1937 (Box 13, Folder 295)
    - Schroeder, Eric, undated (Box 13, Folder 296)
    - Scott, David, 1938 (Box 63, Folder 852)
      Includes essay by Scott
    - Sencourt, R., 1934 (Box 13, Folder 297)
    - Shaw, George Bernard, 1931 December 7 (Box 13, Folder 298)
    - Shelmerdine, Eleanor, 1939, undated (Box 13, Folder 299)
    - Shoosmith, A.G., 1934-1937, undated (Box 13, Folder 300)
    - Sitwell, Edith, Dame, 1937, undated (Box 13, Folder 301)
      Includes photocopies of letter from Sitwell to Byron regarding Dylan Thomas and two letters from Thomas to Byron (dated September and December 1937)
    - Sitwell, Georgia, 1932-1940, undated (Box 13, Folder 302)
    - Sitwell, Osbert, 1937, undated (Box 13, Folder 303)
    - Sitwell, Sacheverell, 1930-1940, undated (Box 13, Folder 304)
    - Sladen, Algy, 1933-1937, undated (Box 13, Folder 305)
    - Spence, Roger, 1933-1934, undated (Box 13, Folder 306)
    - Squire, Rachel, 1939-1940 (Box 13, Folder 307)
    - Squire, Raglan, 1938-1939 (Box 13, Folder 308)
    - Stokes, Adrian Durham, undated (Box 14, Folder 309)
    - Strong, Eugenie, 1932 (Box 14, Folder 310)
    - Strutt, E.L., 1934-1938, undated (Box 14, Folder 311)
    - Stuart, Campbell, Sir, 1939 (Box 14, Folder 312)
    - Stuart-Wortley, Violet, 1936-1940, undated (Box 14, Folder 313)
    - Sunday Times, 1937-1941 (Box 14, Folder 314)
    - Sutro, John, 1929, undated (Box 14, Folder 315)
    - Sykes, Christopher, 1934-1939, undated (Box 14, Folder 316)
    - Sykes, Percy Molesworth, Sir, 1937 (Box 14, Folder 317)
    - "T" General, 1930-1940, undated (Box 14, Folder 318)
    - Tallents, Stephen, 1937-1941, undated (Box 14, Folder 319)
      See also: Background material regarding propaganda and Germany
    - Teague, Heather, 1934-1935, undated (Box 14, Folder 320)
    - Teixidó, Enric, 1932 (Box 14, Folder 321)
    - The Times, 1925-1941, undated (Box 14, Folder 322)
    - Tyler, Ronald, 1932-1934, undated (Box 14, Folder 323)
    - "U" General, 1924-1940, undated (Box 14, Folder 324)
    - "V" General, 1927-1939, undated (Box 14, Folder 325)
    - Victoria and Albert Museum, 1928-1937 (Box 14, Folder 326)
    - "W" General, 1929-1954, undated (Box 14, Folder 327-328)
    - Walker, Alan, undated (Box 14, Folder 329)
    - Walker's Galleries, 1934-1936 (Box 14, Folder 330)
    - Warren, V.B., 1937-1939 (Box 14, Folder 331)
    - Waugh, Evelyn, 1929, undated (Box 14, Folder 332)
    - The Week-end Review, 1932-1933 (Box 14, Folder 333)
    - West, Rebecca, undated (Box 14, Folder 334)
    - Westminster, Loelia, Duchess of, 1940, undated (Box 14, Folder 335)
    - Weir, Thyra, 1930-1934, undated (Box 14, Folder 336)
    - Whittemore, Thomas, 1932-1935 (Box 14, Folder 337)
    - William B. Feakins, Incorporated, 1935 (Box 14, Folder 338)
      Includes draft of Byron's lecture "Persia and Afghanistan"
    - Williams, L.F. Rushbrook, 1931 (Box 14, Folder 339)
    - Williams, W.E., 1938 (Box 14, Folder 340)
    - Willis, Theodora, undated (Box 14, Folder 341)
    - Wilson, Mona, 1931-1941, undated (Box 14, Folder 342)
    - Wimborne, Alice, 1934-1939 (Box 14, Folder 343)
    - Wishart and Company, 1932-1937 (Box 14, Folder 344)
    - Wishaw, H.A., 1934 (Box 14, Folder 345)
    - Woodburn, D.B., 1938-1939 (Box 15, Folder 346)
    - Woolf, Leonard, 1932 May 19 (Box 15, Folder 347)
    - Worthington, Diana, 1939-1940, undated (Box 15, Folder 348)
    - Wyndham, Richard, 1937, undated (Box 15, Folder 349)
    - Wyndham, Violet, 1940, undated (Box 15, Folder 350)
    - "Y" General, 1930-1933, undated (Box 15, Folder 351)
    - Yates, John, 1937-1938, undated (Box 15, Folder 352)
    - Yorke, Adele, 1934, undated (Box 15, Folder 353)
    - Yorke, Henry
      See: Green, Henry
    - Yorke, Maud, 1922-1932, undated (Box 15, Folder 354)
    - Young, G. M. (George Malcolm), 1929-1940, undated (Box 15, Folder 355-356)
      Includes Byron's "An Essay on India: 1930"
    - "Z" General, 1936-1939 (Box 15, Folder 357)
    - Zeitlin, Leon, 1939-1940 (Box 15, Folder 358)
    - Zervos, Skévos, 1925-1928 (Box 15, Folder 359)
    - Identified by first name only, 1931-1941, undated (Box 15, Folder 360-377)
      Includes letters in French
    - Unidentified, 1928-1939, undated (Box 15, Folder 378-380)
      Includes letters in Greek, German, and Persian
    - Unidentified, 1928-1939, undated (Box 16, Folder 381-386)
- Writings, 1866, 1912-1941; Series II; 11.47; (28 boxes)
  The series is organized into six subseries: Major Works, Essays and Articles, Reports, Lectures, Reviews, Other Writings, and Writings of Others. Byron's writings are arranged alphabetically by title. Notebooks and journals from Byron's travels are located in Personal Papers.
  The series documents Byron's writing career with the bulk of material dating from 1912 to 1941. One item from Byron's background research dates from 1866. The series contains drafts, research materials, publicity materials, reviews, and correspondence (related specifically to particular works). The series also includes Byron's work on propaganda during World War II.
  - Major Works
    - The Appreciation of Architecture
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 17, Folder 387)
      - Proof, 1932 (Box 17, Folder 388)
    - The Birth of Western Painting
      - Drafts, holograph, undated (Box 17, Folder 389-391)
      - Draft fragments, typescript, and holograph notes, undated (Box 17, Folder 392-395)
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 18, Folder 396-398)
      - Draft of chapters 2-5, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 18, Folder 399-400)
      - Notes for plates, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 18, Folder 401)
      - Proofs, corrected, 1930 (Box 18, Folder 402-404)
      - Galley proof, corrected, 1929 July 10
      - Reviews, 1931 March 14 (Box 18, Folder 405)
    - The Byzantine Achievement: An Historical Perspective
      - Contract with George Routledge and Sons, 1926 (Box 19, Folder 405a)
      - Background material, undated (Box 19, Folder 406)
      - Draft, holograph, 1923 (Box 19, Folder 407-409)
      - "The Byzantine Succession", draft, typescript, corrected, 1929 (Box 19, Folder 410-411)
      - "The Byzantine Succession", draft, typescript, corrected, 1929 (Box 20, Folder 412)
      - Proof, corrected, 1928 (Box 20, Folder 413)
    - An Essay on India
      - Draft, holograph, 1930 (Box 20, Folder 414)
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 20, Folder 415)
      - Review, 1931 (Box 20, Folder 416)
      - Related correspondence, 1929-1933 (Box 20, Folder 417)
    - Europe in the Looking Glass: Reflections of a Motor Drive from Grimsby to Athens
      - Background material and notes, 1925 (Box 20, Folder 418-420)
      - Draft, holograph, undated (Box 21, Folder 421-423)
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 21, Folder 424-425)
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 21, Folder 426)
      - Proofs, corrected, undated (Box 22, Folder 427-428)
      - Contract with George Routledge and Sons, 1926 (Box 22, Folder 429)
    - First Russia, Then Tibet
      - Background material, 1929-1930 (Box 22, Folder 429a)
        Includes letter from Jigmed Tehring, pass for entry into Tibet, and menu
      - Notebooks, undated (Box 22, Folder 430-435)
      - Notebooks, undated (Box 23, Folder 436-437)
      - Notes, 1924-1930, undated (Box 23, Folder 438)
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 23, Folder 439-440)
      - Proofs, corrected, 1933, undated (Box 23, Folder 441)
      - Galley proofs, 1933 July 7
      - Reviews, 1933
    - Great War book project
      - Background material and notes, undated (Box 23, Folder 442)
    - The Holy Mountain Athos
      See also: The Station: Athos, Treasures and Men
      - Background, undated (Box 24, Folder 443-444)
      - Early drafts, holograph and typescripts, corrected, 1922 and undated (Box 24, Folder 445)
      - Drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected, undated (Box 24, Folder 446)
    - Imperial Pilgrimage
      - Notes and background material, 1936, undated (Box 24, Folder 447-449)
      - Notes and draft, holograph, corrected, undated (Box 24, Folder 450-451)
        Includes related correspondence
      - Drafts, typescript, corrected, 1937, undated (Box 24, Folder 452-453)
    - Innocence and Design
      - Draft, holograph, undated (Box 25, Folder 454-455)
      - "The Rebuilding of Rigg", drafts, typescript and holograph, corrected, undated (Box 25, Folder 456-459)
      - Drafts, typescript and holograph, corrected, undated (Box 25, Folder 460-461)
      - Drafts, typescript and holograph, corrected, undated (Box 26, Folder 462-463)
      - Fragments, undated (Box 26, Folder 464-467)
      - Illustrations, undated (Box 26, Folder 468)
      - Galley proofs, corrected, 1935 May
      - Publicity, 1935 (Box 26, Folder 469)
    - Persian Classical Architecture
      - Background material, 1933 (Box 27, Folder 470)
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 27, Folder 471-473)
    - The Prospect of Being
      - Outline; draft, typescript, corrected for preface; and related correspondence, undated (Box 27, Folder 474)
    - Reading and Sandhurst
      - Draft, holograph, corrected and notes, undated (Box 27, Folder 475)
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, 1924 (Box 27, Folder 476)
    - The Road to Oxiana
      See also: The Road to Oxiana including Afghanistan, Jerusalem, Palestine, Persia, and Syria
      - Background material, 1933 (Box 28, Folder 477)
      - Notebooks, undated (Box 28, Folder 478-482)
      - Draft, holograph, corrected, undated (Box 28, Folder 483-484)
      - "Part II", draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 29, Folder 485-486)
      - "Part III", draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 29, Folder 487-488)
      - Proofs, corrected, 1937 January (Box 29, Folder 489-494)
      - Galley proofs, corrected, circa 1937
      - Reviews, 1937 (Box 30, Folder 495)
    - Shell Guide to Wiltshire
      - Background material, 1934 (Box 30, Folder 496-497)
      - Draft, typescript and holograph, corrected, undated (Box 30, Folder 498)
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 30, Folder 499)
      - Printed version, 1935 April (Box 30, Folder 500)
      - Reviews, 1939 (Box 30, Folder 501)
    - The Station: Athos, Treasures and Men
      See also: The Holy Mountain Athos
      - Notes, undated (Box 30, Folder 502-504)
      - Photographs, undated (Box 31, Folder 505-506)
      - Drawing by Mark Ogilvie-Grant, "I Am a Man of the World", undated (Box 31, Folder 507)
        Pen and ink drawing, published with the title "I Do Want to Be Famous"
      - Draft, holograph, corrected, undated (Box 31, Folder 508-511)
      - Draft, holograph, corrected, undated (Box 32, Folder 512)
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 32, Folder 513-515)
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 32, Folder 516-518)
      - Publicity, undated (Box 32, Folder 519)
      - Reviews, undated (Box 32, Folder 520)
  - Essays and Articles
    - "All These I Learnt", draft, typescript, undated (Box 33, Folder 521)
    - "American Characteristics", draft, typescript, corrected, circa 1939 (Box 33, Folder 521a)
      Includes maps of the U.S. and a letter from the Sunday Times dated 1939 May 17
    - "American Report", draft, holograph, corrected, undated (Box 33, Folder 522)
    - "Architecture and Painting Under Bolshevism", draft, typescript, undated (Box 33, Folder 523)
    - "The Art of Primitive Peoples", draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 33, Folder 524)
    - "Artistic Economics", draft, typescript, undated (Box 33, Folder 525)
    - "Between Tigris and Oxus", printed version, Country Life, 1934 December 1
    - "The Black Pagoda of Kanarak", draft, typescript, corrected; related notes; and printed version, circa 1930 (Box 33, Folder 526)
    - "Britannia's Stage Career", 1931 (Box 33, Folder 527)
    - British Broadcasting Corporation (BBC), European News Department
      - Background, 1940 (Box 33, Folder 528)
      - Drafts, typescript, 1940, undated (Box 33, Folder 529)
    - Burmah-Shell Bulletin
      - Drafts, holograph, corrected, undated (Box 33, Folder 530)
      - Printed versions of articles for issues 1-35, undated (Box 33, Folder 531)
    - "A Censorship Suggestion", drafts, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 33, Folder 532)
    - Articles for The Cherwell, printed versions, 1925 (Box 33, Folder 533-534)
    - "The Chinese Aesthetic", draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 33, Folder 535)
    - "A Clerk's Apology"
      - Drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected, circa 1938 (Box 34, Folder 536-541)
      - Printed version from The New Statesmen and Nation, 1938 March 26
    - "The Climax of Byzantine Art: El Greco", printed version, undated (Box 34, Folder 542)
    - "Communism on the Evidence", draft, holograph and typescript, undated (Box 34, Folder 543)
    - "The Coming Inauguration of India's Capital: Great Architecture on an Imperial Scale at New Delhi", printed version, The Illustrated London News, 1931 January 31
    - "Country Houses in Czechoslovakia", draft, typescript, corrected and related letter, undated (Box 34, Folder 544)
    - "The Death of Chamberlain", draft, typescript, corrected, 1940 November 12 (Box 34, Folder 545)
    - "Doris: Or, The Future of Sin", drafts, holograph and typescript, undated (Box 34, Folder 546)
    - "Drawings of Persia and Afghanistan", printed version from Walker's Monthly, 1934 December
    - "The Fame of Tranquebar", draft, typescript, corrected and background material, 1931, undated (Box 34, Folder 547)
    - "Fascism in the Dodecanese"
      - Background material and notes, 1912-1926 (Box 34, Folder 548-549)
      - Background material and notes, 1912-1926 (Box 35, Folder 550-555)
      - Draft, holograph, corrected, 1926 (Box 35, Folder 556)
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 35, Folder 557)
    - "Future of the India Mail", printed version, The Daily Express, 1929 September 18
    - "The Greenwich Project", printed version, Weekend Review, 1933 1 July (Box 35, Folder 558)
    - "Henry Green Sketch", drafts, typescript, undated (Box 35, Folder 559)
    - "How We Celebrate the Coronation"
      - Drafts, typescript, circa 1937 (Box 35, Folder 560)
      - Reviews, 1937 (Box 35, Folder 561)
    - "Innocents at Home", draft, typescript, corrected, 1935 May (Box 35, Folder 562)
    - "Islamic Monuments: Architectural Glories of Persia," printed version, The Times, 1934 September 28
    - "Lady Irwin's Bathroom", draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 35, Folder 563)
    - "A Land for Heroes", 1940 January 23 (Box 35, Folder 564)
    - "The Last Byzantine Emperor: The Anniversary of May 29th," draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 63, Folder 853)
    - "Light Over Russia", drafts, typescript, corrected, circa 1935 (Box 35, Folder 565)
    - "The Luxury Ship", draft, typescript, undated (Box 35, Folder 566)
    - "Midair Between Moscow and Kazan"
      - Background, circa 1935 (Box 36, Folder 567-569)
      - Drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected, 1935 September (Box 36, Folder 570)
    - "Le Mosaïques de Ste-Sophie", printed version, 1932 May 13
    - "Modern Afghanistan", draft, typescript, undated (Box 36, Folder 571)
    - "The Monasteries of the Meteora", printed version from Country Life, 1932 May 21 (Box 36, Folder 572)
    - "The Need for Information on the Central Asian Question", draft, typescript, 1933 February 14 (Box 36, Folder 573)
    - "New Delhi" articles for Architectural Review
      - Draft, typescript, corrected, 1930 December (Box 36, Folder 574)
      - Proof and printed versions, 1931 January (Box 36, Folder 575)
    - "New Delhi" articles for Country Life
      - Notes and draft fragments, holograph and typescript, corrected, circa 1931 (Box 36, Folder 576)
      - Printed versions, 1931
    - "New Delhi: The Viceroy's House", printed version, The Graphic, 1931 January 24
    - "New Russia", printed version, 1936 March 18
    - "Notes About Oil"
      - Notebook, 1938 (Box 36, Folder 576a)
        Includes notes on Byron's visit with Lucy Butler in Berlin, December 25-28
      - Drafts, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 36, Folder 577-578)
      - Draft, typescript, corrected and final version, 1940 November 19 (Box 36, Folder 579)
    - "The Perfect Party", draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 36, Folder 580)
    - "The Pleasures of Spain", published version, Vogue, 1928 June 13
    - "The Road to Thessaly: On Lord Byron's Track in Epirus", printed version from Country Life, 1931
    - "The Russian Stand on the Pacific", draft, typescript, undated (Box 36, Folder 581)
    - "The Shrine of Khawaja Abu Nasr Parsa at Balkh", printed version from Bulletin of the American Institute for Persian Art and Architecture, 1935 June (Box 36, Folder 582)
    - "Spring Time in Spain", printed version, Harper's Bazaar, 1931 February
    - "Templum Hoc Artium Et Musarum", draft, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 36, Folder 583)
    - "Timurid Architecture"
      - Notes, Before 1937 (Box 37, Folder 584-586)
      - Draft, holograph, corrected, Before 1937 (Box 37, Folder 587)
      - "Monuments in Afghanistan", incomplete draft, typescript, Before 1937 (Box 37, Folder 588)
      - "Islamic Monuments in Afghanistan", drafts, typescript, corrected, Before 1937 (Box 37, Folder 589-590)
        Includes photograph of unidentified monument
      - "Timurid Architecture"
        - Draft, typescript, corrected, Before 1937 (Box 37, Folder 591)
        - Proofs, 1937
    - "The Unspoken Alliance"
      - Outline, holograph; draft, typescript, circa 1938 (Box 37, Folder 592)
      - Draft, typescript, carbon, circa 1938 (Box 37, Folder 593)
    - "The Value of the Dravidian Temple", drafts, typescript, corrected and background material, 1929-1930 (Box 37, Folder 594)
      Accompanied by other articles such as "An Exhibition of Indian Art", "The Original Church of India", "Sukkur Barrage", "The Dinner-Jacket in History"
    - "The Victorian Period", draft, carbon, undated (Box 37, Folder 595)
    - General research materials, 1916-1938 (Box 38, Folder 596-605)
    - General research materials, 1916-1938 (Box 39, Folder 606-617)
    - General research materials, 1916-1938 (Box 40, Folder 618-626)
    - General research materials, 1916-1938 (Box 41, Folder 627-636)
    - Unidentified drafts and notes, undated (Box 41, Folder 637-640)
  - Reports
    - "Report on Journeys in Afghanistan", typescript and related material, 1933-1934 (Box 42, Folder 641)
      Includes eleven photographs of unidentified monuments
    - Background material regarding propaganda and Germany, 1936-1938 (Box 42, Folder 642-644a)
      Includes brochures, pamphlets, leaflets, and an invitation addressed to Thomas Mitford pertaining to the Nuremberg Rally (Reichsparteitag) in 1938
      See also: Tallents, Stephen
    - "Propaganda in Germany", drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected and notes, 1938 (Box 42, Folder 645-646)
    - Drafts (holograph and typescript) and background material for propaganda leaflets, 1938 (Box 42, Folder 647)
    - "Notes on Propaganda in Germany in Peace-Time", drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected, 1938-1939 (Box 42, Folder 648)
      Includes correspondence
    - "Memorandum on a scheme for lectures to inform the peoples of the Empire what they are fighting for", draft, typescript, 1939-1940 (Box 42, Folder 649)
    - "Civil Infiltration as an Instrument of Offense", draft, typescript, carbon and typescript, 1940 (Box 42, Folder 650)
  - Lectures
    - "The Pleasures of Tibet", script for broadcast on BBC Radio, 1931 December 17 (Box 42, Folder 651)
    - "On Persia and Afghanistan", drafts, typescript and related material, 1935, undated (Box 42, Folder 652-653)
    - "What is English Civilisation?" and "The English Home", drafts, typescript and schedule for lecture tour, 1936-1937 (Box 43, Folder 654)
    - Various lectures, drafts, holograph and typescript, undated (Box 43, Folder 655)
  - Reviews
    - Exhibition reviews, 1935-1940, undated (Box 43, Folder 656-659)
    - Book reviews, undated (Box 43, Folder 660-661)
  - Other Writings
    - Letters to the editor, 1925-1939, undated (Box 43, Folder 662)
      Letters to the Editor of The Iran and to Mr. Abdul Qadir regarding article published in The Times in 1934
    - Exhibition catalogues, 1932-1934, undated (Box 43, Folder 663-664)
      Includes catalogue for Byron's exhibition of "Drawings Illustrating a Journey in Persia and Afghanistan" at Walker's Galleries in 1934
    - Foreword for The Wild Asses: A Journey Through Persia, by W.V. Emanuel, draft, typescript, circa 1939 (Box 63, Folder 854)
    - "Itinerary and Aims of a Journey in Russian Turkestan Proposed by Robert Byron, Alastair Graham, and Lord Rosse for March-April 1932", 1931 (Box 63, Folder 855)
    - "Memories of Desmond Parsons", draft, typescript and newspaper clipping of obituary, 1937 (Box 43, Folder 665)
    - "Proposed Magazine on Britain", drafts, typescript, undated (Box 43, Folder 666)
    - "Proposals for War Correspondence", draft, typescript, 1940 December (Box 43, Folder 667)
    - "Remember the Morning," drafts, holograph and typescript, corrected, After 1937 (Box 43, Folder 667a)
      Byron's reminiscences
    - "Thoughts on the Invasion", draft, typescript, undated (Box 43, Folder 668)
    - Untitled draft fragment, typescript, corrected, undated (Box 63, Folder 856)
      Possibly Byron's attempt to write a novel
  - Writings of Others
    Arranged alphabetically by author (when known)
    - Belin, M. "Caractères, Maximes et Pensées de Mir Ali Chir Névâïl", 1866 (Box 43, Folder 669)